Leah: So, to illustrate the principles
of Single Responsibility Principle
[SRP], Separation of Concerns [SoC], and
Abstraction, let’s imagine we want to make
a class which calculates pay after tax.
Look at this example.
As you can see from this example,
our class is responsible for
doing many things, not all of them
related to the main purpose: ‘to
calculate the pay after taxes’.
This could increase the chances of a
bug or make it more complicated to adapt
when changes or updates are needed.
To simplify this, we can apply Single
Responsibility Principles [SRP]
gathering things together that change
for the same reasons, and Separation
of Concern principles [SoC] separating
those that change for different reasons.
So, let’s see this example
again but using SRP and SoC
Here, we have collected all the
things that are relevant to the
single responsibility of the class
– calculating the pay after tax.
This adheres to SRP.
We have also created separate classes
which could change for different
reasons, for example using different
code to generate the payslip or changing
delivery method from email to post.
This adheres to SoC.
Finally using this example again, we
apply the principle of Abstraction
which involves hiding things which are
not required, outside of the class.
There may be information which we do
not want to complicate the code or
which may be sensitive in nature which
can be hidden outside of the class.
In this example, we hide these as
private attributes, so we would
only have access to the pay after
taxes from outside of the class.